Hello everyone. Welcome back to the
channel. In today's tutorial, I'm going
to show you my new consistent face to
video workflow. This workflow includes
new face consistency Laura that helps
preserve your character identity through
the video. Simply provide a reference
image, write your prompt with the
required trigger word, and the workflow
take care of the rest. This workflow is
designed to be low VRAM friendly using
the GGML models, so you don't need a
high-end GPU to get great results. By
the end of this video, you will know how
to generate consistent face to video
results at the best quality with the
minimum VRAM usage. So, without further
ado, let's dive into the tutorial. The
first step that you need to do is
downloading this best face ID Laura,
which will help you a lot to get the
consistent results. So, you can use this
hugging face web link under my
description and download this 2.5 GB
version. You can also here see the
examples or the workflow provided by the
original creator. Okay, once you have
this Laura, you can place it under the
Laura subfolder on the ComfyUI root
folder. So, what this model can help us?
It's an identity-preserving reference to
video Laura built on top of SDXL 2.3
architecture. So, all you need is a
reference photo of a person. They are
strongly suggested face image. After
that, we need a text prompt that will
help us to guide the model to generate
the video, and it will give you a
consistent result while maintaining the
person identity. You can also see here
uh some information about the training
method. They are using a rope source
face, and if you scroll down a little
bit, we can observe the results of this
ID Laura.
We have this photo of a man
combined with the prompt on the the
downside here,
and you can see that it generate
consistent face with the consistent
results. You can observe the same for
all other examples, too.
The videos stay consistent, and it
changes while changing the prompt or the
face image. So, it is a reference to
video, meaning one reference image, and
it will give you a video of that
identity performing the prompt action.
As we saw on the example, the identity
is injected directly by placing a
reference latent on on the frame rope.
It will use our image face in order to
guide the model to generate our video.
The new way of creating a video. You can
see that the model can distinguish
between the source face in order to let
the model know it is a reference, not
the first frame. So, it is a complete
approach compared to the first last
frame workflow that we used to show. And
you can also see here the how you should
provide your reference image. And for
that, I provided some notes in order to
crop the image and forget the other
details. So, you don't need to bother
yourself too much. As for the prompting,
you need to add trigger word, which is
the ref text to video, then describe
your action, sitting, framing, and
camera. They also suggesting that
describing identity attribute will help
you a lot to get consistent and good
results, especially while having speed
animation like turning around or running
and etc. So, we have the the shared
workflow with the prompt enhancer.
However, in order to use the low VRAM
version, you can download my workflow.
Then, all you have to do is drag and
drop the workflow here.
And we are good to go. The workflow was
built on the top of the original author
workflow, but I did some modification in
order to adapt it for the low VRAM GPU
users. So, here you can see that we have
our load face reference
and our different prompt example here.
It is composed of a subgraph, then the
results here with the low resolution
results and second high resolution
results. If you are used to my video,
you know that the LTX can generate works
with two sampling paths. The first one
is low resolution and the second one
it's going to use the LTX upscaler model
A2 provide you the high resolution
results.
And if you take a closer look here at
the subgraph, you can see that we have
the import of our image face, then it's
going to use the auto crop faces in
order to resize
in order to crop the face of our
character
and resize it to this
resolution. After that, this image is
going to be used directly here with this
new identity transfer notes. So, if you
don't see this notes appearing, all you
have to do is going to manager and click
on install missing custom notes.
However, if you have the BFS notes
installed, all you have to do here is go
to the custom notes, search for this BFS
notes and try to update it. It will
install everything automatically for
you. So, once we have our reference face
latent here, you can see that we have
some parameters that will be used in
order to drive our video. But before
that, let's check the model. So, we are
using the GGUE version with separated
audio and video VAE. But for the text
encoder, I am using a regular version of
the Gemma 3 with the LTX 2.3 text
projection. And for the upscaling, I am
always using the 1.5 upscaling model. As
for the Laura, this one is combined with
the Omni NFT in order to get more
consistent and realistic physical world
results. And lastly, we have the best
face ID Laura here with the strength of
one, of course. The resolution is set to
768 and it is both width and height this
time. As for the video duration, they
are giving us example with 5 seconds
video duration, but you can go ahead and
try to increase the number. Okay. Once
we have all these video parameters
settings done, you can see that we will
create our audio empty latent audio with
the empty latent audio. And if you want
to directly use a reference custom
audio, you can go ahead and use this
notes. All you have to do is
placing this audio here. Next, we will
need to create our video latent, and
this one is going to use directly our
base resolution and the total of frames
to create that. After that, this concat
notes going to help us to use the latent
for the identity transfer notes. Okay,
now let's move to the prompting. As you
can see, we have a manual prompt and the
automatic prompt. If you need more
details or you want to obtain uh better
consistency, I strongly suggest you to
activate this button. And based on the
manual prompt, it will give you another
prompt with a detailed description,
which will fit well to your video
generation. So, to do that, you have
here our system prompt with the manual
prompt that's going to be combined.
And after that, the comfy app is going
to create a prompt based on all those
data and instructions.
But if you want to keep it simple, you
can use this prompt as a reference and
try to do other situations or ask
ChatGPT or another AI to create other
situations and example for you.
So, once the prompting is finished, we
can move to this all LT X identity
transfer. This note is going to use the
model, the positive and negative prompt,
the VAE, our latent, and lastly our
reference face, which is a reference
face that is going to be used for each
frame. And it is not the same as
image-to-video generation or first-last
frame video generation. So, this time
the workflow is going to try to generate
the our video with always taken into
account our reference face, which is a
new way of creating video, by the way.
Once all those data are combined, our
sampler custom advance is going to try
to create this video for you.
And since we are working with LTX, so
this is the low resolution version, and
lastly we will create the second or high
resolution version in order to get the
best result as possible. Okay, once it
is finished, you will end up having here
two video. The first one is the low
resolution, and the second one it's your
final video with high resolution. So,
for the first result, I used this image
of a blonde lady and
combined it with the default prompt
default provided with the creator
workflow, and I get this result. You can
see that the workflow managed to create
a video with the aligned face
of our blonde lady. What I did next is I
changed the lady's face with this woman,
and you can also see that it managed to
create the same result with consistent
face. It did not change over the time,
and the details are not as much
impressive. You can see here we have
some
detail loss. However, it To avoid that,
you can always go ahead and try to
increase your base resolution. After
that, I jumped for more known face with
the Spider-Man prompt, and you can see
the results here. It is not very
impressive, and the main reason because
I used this reference image, and I did
not use the auto crop face for the video
generation. So, once I used the auto
crop face, you can see that I am getting
these results. The workflow generated a
video of Messi wearing Spider-Man suit
without changing the color of the
Spider-Man suit. So, it only focuses on
the face. And lastly, I used a different
prompt too. And you can see the results
of this workflow. It can create
consistent video while respecting the
reference face image. Okay, that's it
for today tutorial. If you like this
video, please push the like button for
me. Subscribe to my channel. Leave me
some comments down below. And don't
forget to become a Patreon member of my
Patreon page where you can get early
access to my workflow and ask me for
additional help. You can also go ahead
and become a YouTube premium subscriber
to get early access to my workflow, some
additional workflow tool, and some news
about my next tutorial. So, thank you.